Contact

vanshika.17je003035@am.iiti sm.ac.in

www.linkedin.com/in/itsvalora (LinkedIn) github.com/vanshikaarora (Personal) medium.com/@vanshikaa937 (Blog)

Top Skills

Android Development C++

Object-Oriented Programming (OOP)

Certifications

Smart India Hackathon
Sequence Models
Deep Learning Specialization
Structuring Machine Learning
Projects
Convolutional Neural Networks

Vanshika Arora

SDE Intern'20 &'19 @Microsoft | GSoC'19 @Wikimedia| Competitive Programmer | Android Developer

Dhanbad

Summary

Experienced Software developer with a demonstrated history of working in android development. Skilled in Java,Python (Programming Language), C/C++,Android, Django, SQLite and Firebase. Committed to viable and easily functional app solutions for clients. Over and above, possessing accountable knowledge about Algorithms and Data Structures.

To know more about my projects and contributions- https://github.com/vanshikaarora

Experience

Wikimedia Foundation Mentor at Wikimedia Commons App September 2019 - Present (1 year)

Microsoft Software Developer Intern May 2020 - July 2020 (3 months) Hyderabad, Telangana, India

Google Code-In Mentor at Wikimedia Commons November 2019 - January 2020 (3 months)

Think With Google APAC Member: Get Ahead 2019 - Google APAC July 2019 - August 2019 (2 months)

This virtual program taking place between July 8th to August 30th via live interactive events as well as recommended materials to complete each week.

MindOrks 8 months Blogger at MindOrks January 2019 - August 2019 (8 months)

Android Developer Intern
January 2019 - February 2019 (2 months)
Gurgaon, India

Worked Upon:

An Android Application that supports Audio and Video
The Application uses MVVM architecture for maintenance and testabilty
Other Components like Dagger and ButterKnife were also used in the
development of the Application

Microsoft Software Developer Intern May 2019 - July 2019 (3 months) Hyderabad, Telangana, India

Bobble AI Technologies Android Developer Intern December 2018 - December 2018 (1 month) Gurgaon, India

Roles and Responsibilities

- 1. Responsible for introducing Dynamic Whatsapp Sticker's into Bobble app.
- 2. Converting the existing Bobble png images to suitable format and add it to whatsapp as whatsapp stickers.
- 3. Introducing the Driving Assistant in Bobble app. While driving the app reads out whatsapp notifications to the user and then records their response as an audio to be sent via WhatsApp.

Cyber Labs
Android Application Developer
January 2018 - December 2018 (1 year)
Dhanbad Area, India

Concetto IIT(ISM),Dhanbad Android Developer September 2018 - October 2018 (2 months)

Android application developer of Concetto App

Concetto is the annual Techo-Management fest of IIT(ISM) Dhanbad. Which is also regarded as the largest fest of eastern India.

ACM, Association for Computing Machinery

Member

October 2017 - October 2018 (1 year 1 month)

Dhanbad Area, India

Mic.Drop Toastmasters Club 10 months

Sergeant at Arams at Mic, Drop Toastmasters Club December 2017 - June 2018 (7 months)

Dhanbad Area, India

Member at Mic.Drop Toastmasters Club September 2017 - November 2017 (3 months) Dhanbad Area, India

Education

Indian Institute of Technology (Indian School of Mines), Dhanbad Integrated Master of Technology, Mathematics and Computing · (2017 - 2022)

St George's college, Agra, India High School · (2015)